Tibet
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Tibet, 2.1.3.5
  - Tibet: Monks, 1949; 11 (Box 1533)
    - Monk for. mins. [foreign minister] walking towards D.L.'s [Dalai Lama's] palace, 10
    - Verso: Monk for. mins. [foreign minister] walking towards D.L.'s [Dalai Lama's] palace, 10-verso
    - Sera Goupa, second largest monastery in Tibet; page 267, 11
    - Verso: Sera Goupa, second largest monastery in Tibet; page 267, 11-verso
    - "Everything in this palace chapel is of solid gold-except the red-robed monk, and the offerings of silk scarves, butter and grain. Note the design of the elaborate golden vessel and of the supporting dragon"; page 259; Return: Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr., 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, 12
    - Verso: "Everything in this palace chapel is of solid gold-except the red-robed monk, and the offerings of silk scarves, butter and grain. Note the design of the elaborate golden vessel and of the supporting dragon"; page 259; Return: Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr., 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, 12-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and two Tibetan monks] [3 copies], 13
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. and four Tibetan monks], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. and four Tibetan monks] [2 copies], 15
    - [Four monks in Tibet] [3 copies], 16
    - [Group of Tibetan monks], 17
  - Tibet: Monks, 1949; 12 (Box 1533)
    - Blowing monastery trumpet on Chag Pari Hill; T-269, 1
    - Verso: Blowing monastery trumpet on Chag Pari Hill; T-269, 1-verso
    - A monk noble, 2
    - Verso: A monk noble, 2-verso
    - Monks in courtyard at Sera Monastery; T 195, 3
    - Verso: Monks in courtyard at Sera Monastery; T 195, 3-verso
    - [Monks in courtyard at Sera Monastery], 4
    - [Monks in courtyard at Sera Monastery], 5
    - Golden image of an early Dalai Lama; T 217, 6
    - Verso: Golden image of an early Dalai Lama; T 217, 6-verso
    - [Golden image of an early Dalai Lama], 7
    - [Golden image of an early Dalai Lama], 8
    - [Tibetan monk at monastery] [2 copies], 9
    - [Tibetan monk at monastery], 10
    - [Three monks in Tibet], 11
    - [Monk standing in front of an elaborate door in Tibet], 12
    - [Two elderly monks in Tibet], 13
  - Tibet: Art, undated; 13 (Box 1533)
    - [Tibetan painter], 1
    - [Tibetan painting], 2
  Box 1534
- Tibet, 2.1.3.5
  - Tibet: Officials and nobles, 1949; 1 (Box 1534)
    - Shakabpa, family and L.T. in front of country house; T-170 [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: Shakabpa, family and L.T. in front of country house; T-170, 1-verso
    - 2 For. [Foreign] Ministers and L.T. seated; T-184 [2 copies], 2
    - Verso: 2 For. [Foreign] Ministers and L.T. seated; T-184, 2-verso
    - Noble-mounted; T 167 [3 copies], 3
    - Verso: Noble-mounted; T 167, 3-verso
    - [The Tibet State Oracle] [4 copies], 4
    - Tsarong Shape, whose horse broke LT's hip on way out; T-190 [5 copies], 5
    - Verso: Tsarong Shape, whose horse broke LT's hip on way out; T-190, 5-verso
    - Dorje Changwaba makes sure we won't go hungry; L.T., Dorje and servant with gift of lamb; T 165 [3 copies], 6
    - Verso: Dorje Changwaba makes sure we won't go hungry; L.T., Dorje and servant with gift of lamb; T 165, 6-verso
    - T-186 [Tibetan official on horse], 7
    - Verso: T-186, 7-verso
  - Tibet: Potala, 1949; 2 (Box 1534)
    - Near top of Potala; L. T. in silhouette; T-262, 1
    - Verso: Near top of Potala; L. T. in silhouette; T-262, 1-verso
    - Potala looking up from street; T-260, 2
    - Verso: Potala looking up from street; T-260, 2-verso
    - [Potala, Tibet] [3 copies], 3
    - Verso: T-254, 3-verso
    - [Polata off in the distance, Tibet], 4
    - Verso: T-255, 4-verso
  - Tibet: Street scenes, 1949; 3 (Box 1534)
    - Place in galley 37 just before "Then entrance to Horbu Linga is flanked---" Caption: Where those bound for Horbu Linga pause for refreshment---blocks of yak cheese, hard cookies, and "Virginia 10's." Cigarette smoking theoretically is taboo in Tibet; only a few indulge; T-128, 1
    - Verso: Place in galley 37 just before "Then entrance to Horbu Linga is flanked---" Caption: Where those bound for Horbu Linga pause for refreshment---blocks of yak cheese, hard cookies, and "Virginia 10's." Cigarette smoking theoretically is taboo in Tibet; only a few indulge; T-128, 1-verso
    - Carrying bundles of reeds; T-135, 2
    - Verso: Carrying bundles of reeds; T-135, 2-verso
    - Women on street, mule on right; T-143, 3
    - Verso: Women on street, mule on right; T-143, 3-verso
    - Yaks and children on street; T-133, 4
    - Verso: Yaks and children on street; T-133, 4-verso
    - Cutting blocks of stone, 5
    - Verso: Cutting blocks of stone, 5-verso
    - Lhasa street - dog foreground; T-120, 6
    - Verso: Lhasa street - dog foreground; T-120, 6-verso
    - [Lhasa street], 7
    - Verso: T-119, 7-verso
    - [Oxen in Lhasa] [5 copies], 8
    - Verso: T-121, 8-verso
    - [Two Tibetan women], 9
  - Tibet: Summer festival, 1949; 4 (Box 1534)
    - Drama tent; T-144, 1
    - Verso: Drama tent; T-144, 1-verso
    - page 215 [Actor performing at the Summer Festival in Tibet], 2
    - Verso: page 215, 2-verso
    - Drama - King kneeling; T-148, 3
    - Verso: Drama - King kneeling; T-148, 3-verso
    - Dance - narrator on right; T-149, 4
    - Verso: Dance - narrator on right; T-149, 4-verso
    - Drama - narrator and 4 others; T-150 [2 copies], 5
    - Verso: Drama - narrator and 4 others; T-150, 5-verso
    - Play - demon - med [medium] shot; T-153, 6
    - Verso: Play - demon - med [medium] shot; T-153, 6-verso
    - Drama - devil - close-up, 7
    - Verso: Drama - devil - close-up, 7-verso
  - Tibet: Lowell Thomas, 1949; 5 (Box 1534)
    - Chogpon, middle, and his monk brother, and L.T.; T-10 [3 copies], 1
    - Verso: Chogpon, middle, and his monk brother, and L.T.; T-10, 1-verso
    - Rai Badahur Sonam [with Lowell Thomas]; T-287, 2
    - Verso: Rai Badahur Sonam [with Lowell Thomas]; T-287, 2-verso
    - [Rai Badahur Sonam with Lowell Thomas]; 290, 3
    - With a Brahmaputra (Tsang Po) boatman; T-294 [2 copies], 4
    - Verso: With a Brahmaputra (Tsang Po) boatman; T-294, 4-verso
    - [Rimshi Doti and Lowell Thomas], T-24, 5
    - L.T. and glacier, Karo La; T-47, 6
    - Verso: L.T. and glacier, Karo La; T-47, 6-verso
    - L.T. and presents, close-up; T-225 [2 copies], 7
    - Verso: L.T. and presents, close-up; T-225, 7-verso
    - L.T. and presents for Dalai Lama included two tiger skulls inlaid with gold and silver; T-224, 8
    - Verso: L.T. and presents for Dalai Lama included two tiger skulls inlaid with gold and silver; T-224, 8-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas on white donkey] [2 copies], 9
    - Verso: T 712, 9-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas with an abacus in a Tibetan shop] [5 copies], 10
    - Verso: T-132, 10-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas being carried in a chair in Tibet] [2 copies], 11
    - [Group of six in Tibet], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others in a car in Tibet] [2 copies], 13
  - Tibet: Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1949; 6 (Box 1534)
    - Rai Badahur Sonam [on right with Lowell Thomas, Jr., center] [8 copies], 1
    - Verso: Rai Badahur Sonam [on right with Lowell Thomas, Jr., center], 1-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. presenting the Tibetan scroll to President Truman], 2
    - Note: PRESENTS TIBETAN SCROLL TO PRESIDENT: Lowell Thomas, Jr., son of the radio commentator, is shown in Washington, D.C., Nov. 9 [1949], with the Tibetan scroll he presented to President Truman. The scroll was brought from Tibet by the elder Thomas a few weeks ago. The scroll, bearing a message in Tibetan characters, handwritten with a piece of bamboo on a parchment from the bark of a tree, was presented to Thomas by two top officials of the Dalai Lama's government. Lowell Thomas, Sr., injured in a fall from a horse in Tibet, was brought home by a rescue team sent into Tibet by the Indian government., 3
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. holding the Tibetan scroll], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr.(?) in Tibet] [8 copies], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. in Tibet], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas holding a "Lodwick's School of Aeronautics" banner in Tibet], 7
    - Verso: T-293, 7-verso
  - Tibet: Lowell Thomas, Jr. (Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet book signings), 1950; 7 (Box 1534)
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. signing Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. and two ladies at the Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet book signing], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. signing Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet for his fans], 3
  - Tibet: Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1949; 8 (Box 1534)
    - [Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas Jr. in Tibet], 1
    - Verso:T-285, 1-verso
    - LT, Sr. and LT, Jr, There were many fascinating sights to be seen on the rocky road to Lhasa-so many that the travelers didn't take time out to shave; T-296, 2
    - Verso: LT, Sr. and LT, Jr, There were many fascinating sights to be seen on the rocky road to Lhasa-so many that the travelers didn't take time out to shave; T-296, 2-verso
  - Tibet: Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1949; 9 (Box 1534)
    - L.T., Jr. and L.T., Sr. with 3 Tibetan noblemen-- the Potala in Lhasa, Tibet, in background; 100 rooms, golden domes [left to right: Lowell Thomas, Jr., Rimshi Kyipup, Minister of War, Luishahr Dzaza Lama, Dorje Changwaba and Lowell Thomas], 1
    - Verso: L.T., Jr. and L.T., Sr. with 3 Tibetan noblemen-- the Potala in Lhasa, Tibet, in background; 100 rooms, golden domes [left to right: Lowell Thomas, Jr., Rimshi Kyipup, Minister of War, Luishahr Dzaza Lama, Dorje Changwaba and Lowell Thomas], 1-verso
    - Note: L.T., Jr.; Rimshi Kyipup, Monk Minister of War; Dorje Changwaba; L.T., Sr.; Potala in distance, 2
  - Tibet: Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. (wearing Tibetan hats), 1949; 10 (Box 1534)
    - L.T. in Tibetan hat; wearing red silk ceremonial scarf presented to him by The Dalai Lama, 1
    - Verso: L.T. in Tibetan hat; wearing red silk ceremonial scarf presented to him by The Dalai Lama, 1-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas Jr. in Tibetan dress], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas Jr. dressed in Tibetan garb], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. dressed in Tibetan clothes], 4
    - L.T., Jr. wearing cap of a Tibetan nomad, 5
    - Verso: L.T., Jr. wearing cap of a Tibetan nomad, 5-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. wearing Tibetan nomad hat], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. wearing Tibetan nomad hat], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. in Tibetan clothes holding Tibetan teacups], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. holding two Tibetan teacups], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas in Tibetan clothes holding two Tibetan teacups], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. drinking out of a Tibetan teacup], 11
  - Tibet: Yak skin boats, 1949; 11 (Box 1534)
    - Note: [Navigation on Tibetan rivers is in Yak skin boats. This one, although large enough to carry twenty people or six horses, is so light that the boat-man can put it on his back and carry it upstream. And, that is only way of getting it up a river. Herd of Yak. This of course is the animal on which the Tibetan depends on so much. Without Yak it is doubtful there would be human life on the "roof of the world". Instead of saying "how do you do" or using some other greeting familiar to us, Tibetans exchange silk scarves. These they place over each others wrists. Tibetan artist. Art is an important part of Tibetan life. There are many artists. They were constantly at work decorating the innumerable monestaries or Lamaseries, also making pictures for homes and for public buildings. Monks recieving their noon-day allotment of barley flour. One out of every four males in Tibet becomes a Lama, a monk. So this could be considered one of the routine activities of Tibet. Tibetan monk blowing a trumpet on the roof of a monestery om tje capitol city of Lhasa. Some trumpets are made from human thigh bones. Others of great shells imported over the lofty mountains from China or India, and still longer trumpets -- some eight, ten, and twelve (-2-) feet long are made of brass. Trumpets and horns are beling blown from the roofs of the monasteries almost constantly., 1
    - [Tibetan Tak skin boats] [2 copies], 2
    - Verso: T-100 [Tibetan Yak skin boats], 2-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and Tibetan locals in a Yak skin boat], 3
    - Verso: T-106 [Lowell Thomas and Tibetan locals in a Yak skin boat], 3-verso
    - [Yak skin boat in Tibet], 4
    - Verso: T-110 [Yak skin boat in Tibet], 4-verso
    - [Tibetan Yak skin boats propped up on oars], 5
    - Verso: T-113 [Tibetan Yak skin boats propped up on oars], 5-verso
    - Man carrying his boat; close-up carrying yak skin boat; T-114 [2 copies], 6
    - Verso: Man carrying his boat; close-up carrying yak skin boat; T-114, 6-verso
  - Tibet: Color conversions, 1949; 12 (Box 1534)
    - L.T. and The Kashag, Dalai Lama's no. 1 cabinet-1 monk and 2 nobles; T-254, 1
    - Verso: L.T. and The Kashag, Dalai Lama's no. 1 cabinet-1 monk and 2 nobles; T-254, 1-verso
    - [Native Tibetan people], 2
    - [Tibetan woman in traditional Tibetan dress], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas and two native Tibetans], 4
    - [Two women in Tibet], 5
    - [Tibetan woman and man], 6
    - [Tibetan person in traditional dress], 7
    - [Two Tibetan women standing in front of a building], 8
    - [Line of Tibetan people on horses], 9
    - [The Potala Palace in the distance], 10
    - [The Potala Palace], 11
  - Tibet: Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet by Lowell Thomas, Jr. [illustrations], 1949; 13 (Box 1534)
    - Caption: [frontispiece] Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age, 1
    - Caption: [pages 16-17] Paying with Tibetan copper coins the coolies who helped us on one day's journey. Their daily wage, less than fifty cents, is a good sum in the Orient [2 copies], 2
    - Caption: [page 33] The Foreign Ministers, Luishahr Dzaza Lama and Surkhang Dzaza. Their office has the responsibility of directing the negotiations with Red China for a peaceful settlement of China's claim to Tibet as a Chinese province [2 copies], 3
    - Verso: The Foreign Ministers, Luishahr Dzaza Lama and Surkhang Dzaza, 3-verso
    - Caption: [page 47] Harishwar Dayal, I.C.S., and his wife were our hosts at Gangtok. As the Indian political officer in Sikkim, Mr. Dayal is in charge of India-Tibet affairs. He gave us the good news of our final clearance for entry to Tibet [6 copies], 4
    - Verso: He helped the expedition get started. Harishwar Dayal, I.C.S., Gov't. of India Political Officer at Gangtok, Sikkim, and his wife, for 9 yrs. tennis champ of India, 4-verso
    - Caption: [page 49] Our caravan is loaded in the backyard of the Indian residency at Gangtok, as we prepare to journey into the mountains of Sikkim on the first leg of the long trail that is to lead us to the Dalai Lama's Holy City [3 copies], 5
    - Verso: Expedition loading in Dayal backyard-Gangtok, Sikkim, 5-verso
    - Caption: [page 55] My father recording a broadcast by candlelight in a dark bungalow. We made a point of preparing a five- to ten-minute recording each evening. One day Dad would do the job, the next evening it would be my turn, 6
    - [copy from book] Caption: Fig. 12-4. Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. shown while recording material in Tibet for subsequent broadcast over the Columbia Broadcasting System. The recorder shown is one of the first Minitapes produced. (From, and copyrighted 1950 by, Lowell Thomas, Jr., Out of this World, New York: The Greystone Press, page 55); rent model uses, as power sources, a 6-votl miniature storage battery, 7
    - Caption: [page 57] The principal caravan route through the Himalayas into Tibet is narrow and stony. Down this trail for countless centuries have come, just as shown here, Tibetan caravans carrying wool, yak tails and musk to India [2 copies], 8
    - Caption: [page 59] L.T., Sr., leading our caravan through the mountains of Sikkim on the climb to Nathu-La, the pass on the Tibetan frontier. This is one of those rare moments of the whole Sikkim journey when it wasn't raining Verso: Trail of big stones; L.T. hatless [2 copies], 9
    - Verso: Trail of big stones. L.T. hatless. Tibet., 9-verso
    - Caption: [page 67] In the valley below is the first monastery to be seen along our trail-Kargyu Gompa. The monks of Kargyu Gompa are members of the Red Hat sect and, as such, may go home at night, drink beer and take wives Verso: L.T. looking down on 1st monastery in Tibet [2 copies], 10
    - Verso: L.T. looking down on 1st monastery in Tibet., 10-verso
    - Caption: [page79] Above, the Tromo Trochi, wearing a costume of black yak wool (note the turquoise-and-pearl earring), endorses our U. S. passports [5 copies], 11
    - Caption: [page 79] Below, the lamyik, Tibetan guarantee of safe conduct, with the Dalai Lama's seal [3 copies], 12
    - Verso: Tibetan Lamyik, Tibetan guarantee of safe conduct, with the Dalai Lama's seal, 12-verso
  - Tibet: Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet by Lowell Thomas, Jr. [illustrations] [color photographs], 1949; 14 (Box 1534)
    - Caption: [pages 80-81] Across the valley from the Potala, one of the wonders of the world. On top of the palace rest the sparkling gold-roofed crypts of departed Dalai Lamas. With the Thomases: Rimshi Kyipup, Luishahr Dzaza Lama and Dorje Changwaba [10 copies], 1
  Box 1535
- Tibet, 2.1.3.5
  - Tibet: Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet by Lowell Thomas, Jr. [illustrations], 1949; 1 (Box 1535)
    - [15 copies] Caption: [pages 80-81] Across the valley from the Potala, one of the wonders of the world. On top of the palace rest the sparkling gold-roofed crypts of departed Dalai Lamas. With the Thomases: Rimshi Kyipup, Luishahr Dzaza Lama and Dorje Changwaba, 1
  - Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet by Lowell Thomas, Jr. [illustrations], 1949; 2 (Box 1535)
    - [mounted photograph, 11 copies] Caption: [pages 80-81] Across the valley from the Potala, one of the wonders of the world. On top of the palace rest the sparkling gold-roofed crypts of departed Dalai Lamas. With the Thomases: Rimshi Kyipup, Luishahr Dzaza Lama and Dorje Changwaba, 1
  - Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet by Lowell Thomas, Jr. [illustrations] [promotional color postcards], 1949; 3 (Box 1535)
    - [postcard, muliple copies] Caption: [pages 80-81] Across the valley from the Potala, one of the wonders of the world. On top of the palace rest the sparkling gold-roofed crypts of departed Dalai Lamas. With the Thomases: Rimshi Kyipup, Luishahr Dzaza Lama and Dorje Changwaba Caption: [postcard] The Lowell Thomases with Tibetan officials, in front of the 1,000-room Potala Palace - built by hand - almost as high as the Empire State Building; the sun was too much for Lowell Jr.'s eyes; and the Communists want to "liberate" this peace-loving country!, 1
  - Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet by Lowell Thomas, Jr. [illustrations] [promotional color postcards], 1949; 4 (Box 1535)
    - [postcard, muliple copies] Caption: [pages 80-81] Across the valley from the Potala, one of the wonders of the world. On top of the palace rest the sparkling gold-roofed crypts of departed Dalai Lamas. With the Thomases: Rimshi Kyipup, Luishahr Dzaza Lama and Dorje Changwaba Caption: [postcard] The Lowell Thomases with Tibetan officials, in front of the 1,000-room Potala Palace - built by hand - almost as high as the Empire State Building; the sun was too much for Lowell Jr.'s eyes; and the Communists want to "liberate" this peace-loving country!, 1
  - Out of This World: Across the Himalayas to Forbidden Tibet by Lowell Thomas, Jr. [illustrations], 1949; 5 (Box 1535)
    - Caption: [pages 80-81] This stone staircase leads into the main temple of the Potala. The people of Lhasa take the sacred walk around the palace - a five-mile hike - at least once a year, 1
    - Caption: [pages 80-81] This stone staircase leads into the main temple of the Potala. The people of Lhasa take the sacred walk around the palace - a five-mile hike - at least once a year, 2
    - Caption: [page 86] Chogpon Nima Gyabu, wearing an earring under his campaign hat, served as our military escort throughout the journey. Near the end of each day's march he would gallop ahead to arrange our accommodations, 3
    - Caption: [page 86] Chogpon Nima Gyabu, wearing an earring under his campaign hat, served as our military escort throughout the journey. Near the end of each day's march he would gallop ahead to arrange our accommodations, 4
    - Caption: [page 90] L. T., Sr., and Interpreter Tsewong on the Tibetan plateau. We traveled these barren heights during the early hours of daylight to avoid the fierce winds. (The white on Dad's cheek is zinc oxide, for sunburn), 5
    - Verso: L.T. and Tsewong Nymgyal-mounted, 5-verso
    - Caption: [page 93] The famous black yak-hair tent of the nomad, which has not changed its form through the centuries. These herdsmen are fortunate enough to have wood for fuel-they have carried it over the passes from Bhutan, 6
    - Verso: Tibetan nomads - Mt. Chomolhari in rear, 6-verso
    - Caption: [page 95] At Phari, Rimshi Dote offers us silk scarves and presents of food. Later he gave us a bolt of tough yak cloth in exchange for a promise to send him from America a like amount of green gabardine cloth for a gown, 7
    - Verso: Rimchi Doti [Rimshi Dote], 7 feet tall, going thru the silk scarf ceremony with L.T. at Phari Dzong, Tibet; 14,900 feet, 7-verso
    - Caption: [page 95] At Phari, Rimshi Dote offers us silk scarves and presents of food. Later he gave us a bolt of tough yak cloth in exchange for a promise to send him from America a like amount of green gabardine cloth for a gown, 8
    - Verso: Rimshi Dorje greets us at Phari with the silk scarf ceremony, 8-verso
    - Caption: [page 97] We overtake coolies carrying crated beds the three hundred miles from India to Lhasa. In many places, the trail is too narrow to be negotiated by pack animals (other than human ones) loaded with such burdens, 9
    - Verso: Bearers carrying beds to some noble at Lhasa, 9-verso
    - Caption: [page 97] We overtake coolies carrying crated beds the three hundred miles from India to Lhasa. In many places, the trail is too narrow to be negotiated by pack animals (other than human ones) loaded with such burdens, 10
    - Caption: [page 109] Hugh Richardson, the last Britisher in the Indian Foreign Service, was the representative of the Indian Government in Tibet. Here he is surrounded by ladies of the Tsarong family, who rank high Tibet, 11
    - Caption: [page 109] Hugh Richardson, the last Britisher in the Indian Foreign Service, was the representative of the Indian Government in Tibet. Here he is surrounded by ladies of the Tsarong family, who rank high Tibet, 12
    - Caption: [page 109] Hugh Richardson, the last Britisher in the Indian Foreign Service, was the representative of the Indian Government in Tibet. Here he is surrounded by ladies of the Tsarong family, who rank high Tibet, 13
    - Caption: [page 112] Yak caravans, loaded with wool, pass Mt. Chomolhari on their way to India. When used as a pack animal, the yak delights in bolting from the trail into the rocks, usually managing to smash the burden from his back, 14
    - Verso: Yak caravan beneath Mt. Chowolban[?], 14-verso
    - Caption: [page 113] All plowing in Tibet is done with yaks and wooden plows. In spite of the country's mountainous nature there is more than enough arable land. The need, in view of the declining population, is for more plow hands, 15